《越狱》前情提要
Previously on Prison Break:
我没有杀他，麦可
I didn't kill that man, Michael.
如果你没有杀戴伦斯史泰门
If you didn't kill Terrence steadman...
怎么有人有办法可以栽赃给你？
...how did someone make it look like you did?
-我要救你出去 -不可能的
- I'm getting you out of here. - That's impossible.
如果监狱是你设计的 就有可能
Not if you designed the place, it isn't.
门最好是开的
It better be open, bro.
-你这是要我犯法 -我只是要你犯个小错
- You're asking me to break the law. - I ask you to make a mistake.
假装忘记锁门
Forget to lock up.
可以进去了
We're in.
是谁杀了戴伦斯史泰门？
Who killed Terrence steadman?
没有人 戴伦斯史泰门还活着
Nobody. Terrence steadman's still alive.
你好，戴伦斯
Hello, Terrence.
启动警报
Sound the alarm.
在这里
Hey! Hey!
不！不！
No! No!
-现在怎么办？ -我们要逃亡
- What do we do now? - We run.
这些逃犯是谁？
The escapees, who were they?
我这里有名单
Got a list right here.
麻烦念给我听
Read it to me, if you could.
麦可史柯菲，结构工程师
Michael scofield, structural engineer.
持枪抢劫被判入狱五年
Five years for armed robbery,
班哲明迈尔斯富兰克林
Benjamin Miles Franklin.
前陆军士兵 持有赃物被判入狱八年
Former U, S, Army, Eight years for possession of stolen goods,
约翰亚布兹
John Abruzzi.
家族犯罪组织的老大
Don of the crime family of the same name,
教唆杀人被判无期徒刑，不得假释
Life without parole for conspiracy to commit murder.
查尔斯帕托西克，绰号疯仔
Charles "Haywire" Patoshik,
二级杀人罪，入狱60年
sixty years for second-degree murder.
费南多苏克
Fernando sucre.
强盗罪入狱五年
Five years for aggravated robbery,
大卫阿普斯基，外号中间人
David "Tweener" Apolskis.
重大窃盗罪入狱五年
Five years for grand larceny.
泰迪包威，绰号茶包
Theodore "T-Bag" Bagwell.
绑架、强奸和一级杀人 被判六次无期徒刑
Life for six counts of kidnapping, rape and first-degree murder.
还有林克柏劳
And Lincoln Burrows.
预计下周处死 他谋杀雷诺兹总统的弟弟
Scheduled to die next week for the murder of President Reynolds' brother,
他们翻墙出去已经多久了？
How long has it been since they got over the wall?
昨晚八点逃出去的
Eight o'clock last night,
-史柯菲，他和柏劳是兄弟 -没错
- scofield. He and Burrows are brothers. - That's right.
他是越狱的主谋
And he's the mastermind of this whole thing,
他们是这么说的
That's what they're saying.
我要他所有的资料
I want everything they've got on him.
他们在哪里？
Where are they?
那是什么声音？
What the hell is that?
我们走
Let's go.
-我们要跑到另一边才行 -什么？
- We gotta make it to the other side! - What?
-跑到铁轨另一边 -你疯了
- Make it to the other side! - Crazy!
-快点 -快跑
- Come on! - Come on, run!
快跑，动作快
We gotta go! Run! Let's go! Move it, move it!
-快点 -火车速度加快了
- Go! - The thing is gaining speed, man!
-火车太快了！ -穿过去！
- It's going too fast! - Go through!
-什么？ -穿过去
- What? - Go through!
麦可
Michael!
不要开枪
Hold your fire!
站住 我会开枪的，史柯菲
Freeze! I will gun you down, scofield!
麦可，快来
Michael, come on.
-直升机在哪里？ -他们回地上加油
- Where's the aerial unit? - They're back on the ground refueling.
该死的家伙
Son of a bitch.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：全力缉捕
先生，媒体准备好了
Sir, the media is ready.
可以的话，我想稍微谈谈 约翰魏克斯布思
I'd like to talk about John Wilkes Booth for a moment, if I could.
谋杀林克总统的人
Abraham Lincoln's killer.
12天
Twelve days.
花了这么久才找到他
That's how long it took to find him.
他当时在日记中写下 阴影是他的朋友
In his journal during this period, he wrote that the shadow was his friend...
夜晚是他的世界
...the night his domain.
他承认了，那股驱使罪犯
He acknowledged that neuroses driving the criminal,,,
犯罪的原动力
,,, to commit the original crime is compounded,,,
会因逃亡而加大
,,, magnified by flight,
是因为紧追在后 警犬的声响
By the sounds of dogs at his heels,
恐惧变成妄想症
Fear becomes paranoia.
妄想最后变成精神病
Paranoia, ultimately psychosis,
我提到这件事是因为 140年后
I bring this up because in 140 years...
逃犯的基本心态仍未改变
...the fundamental mind of the escaped man has not changed.
逃犯一样是人，一样会害怕
The escaped man is still human, he is still afraid...
一样会不顾一切企图逃亡
...and he will stop at nothing in his attempted flight.
不过我们很幸运
Fortunately for us,,,
我们的对手只有影子和夜晚相助
,,, while our quarry has shadow and night as his ally,,,
而我们有更得力的助手
...we have something far greater.
就是电视
Television.
我期望国内所有在看电视的人
I would encourage everyone who is watching...
请仔细看看这些面孔
...everyone in this country, to take a good look at these faces.
这八人是现在美国的头号通缉犯
These men right here are now the eight most wanted men in America.
我以为计划周详 你看到有多少人在追我们吗？
I thought I thought this out. You saw all those guys back there?
重点是他们在后面，我们在上面
The key is they're back there and we're up here.
这样能维持多久？
Yeah. And how long is that gonna last?
对，尤其我们现在一毛钱也没有
Especially since we don't have a pot to piss in...
都要感谢亚布兹神奇消失的飞机
...thanks to Abruzzi's magically disappearing jet.
反正你也上不了飞机
You were never gonna be on that plane.
别以为我不知道你打算去哪
Don't think I don't know where you were going.
-我要去哪里？ -喔，我不知道
- Where am I going? - Oh, I don't know.
犹他州？
Utah?
你打算何时才告诉我们钱的事？
You planning on telling us about the money?
什么钱？
What money?
五百万美金 威莫兰埋在犹他州沙漠的钱
Five million dollars that Westmoreland planted in the desert in Utah.
-你根本不知道你在说什么 -是你希望我不知道
- You don't know what you're talking about. - You wish I didn't know.
等等，什么钱？
Wait, wait. What money?
典狱长
Warden.
FBI现在介入太早了，不是吗？
It's a little early for the FBI to be showing up, don't you think?
我明白，调查还是由你主导
Look, I get it. It's still your investigation.
但是只要逃犯越过州界 就是联邦事务了
Once those criminals cross state lines, it'll become a federal matter.
-不会发生这种事的 -希望你是对的
- Yeah, well, that is not gonna happen. - I hope you're right.
所以我建议你 先撇开任何政治成见
That's why I suggest that we cut through any interagency politics from the outset.
-一切坦白透明化 -那当然
- Full transparency. - Absolutely.
很好
Good.
那么或许可以跟我谈谈 丹奎迪医生
Then maybe you can tell me about Dr. Tancredi.
没什么好谈的
There's nothing to tell.
我听说她有可能帮助逃犯逃亡
From what I'm hearing, she may have abetted the escapees.
她打开门让他们逃出去
Opened the door that allowed them to get out.
-我说过，没什么好谈的 -你不太坦白，典狱长
- Like I said, there's nothing to tell. - You're not being very transparent, warden.
-听着，我不谈下属的事 -也许你应该谈
- Look, I don't discuss my staff. - Maybe you should...
因为她可能是整件事的关键
...because she may be the key to this thing.
我们需要找她谈谈
We need to speak with her.
曼宏先生，就现在而言 她不会跟任何人谈的
Well, right now, Mr. Mahone, she's not gonna be speaking with anyone.
情况如何？
How we doing?
点滴提供她水分
Well, the IVs are hydrating her.
每半小时替她注射 半毫克芉酸那啰克酸
We've got her on naloxone infusion. Half-milligram per hour.
你认为苏醒的机会有多大？
What do you think the chances are?
我们尽力了 一切得靠她自己
Well, we've done everything on our end. It's really up to her.
她坚持就能活命，放弃就会死
Either she fights and lives, or she quits and dies.
你在做什么
Hey, what do you think...?
你想做什么随便你
Do whatever thing you've gotta do, man.
对了，小子
Oh, and boy...
要是你敢报警，我手上的东西
If you call the cops, I will put this thing right here...
就会插进你的眼睛
...in your eye.
谢谢
Thank you.
他是结构工程师？
Structural engineer, huh?
这种人很少会有这么多刺青在身上
Not the kind you'd expect to get that much ink.
应该说不可能刺青
Not the kind at all.
你觉得这种刺青 要多久才能完成？
How long do you think it'd take to get something like that done?
一百小时，两百小时
A hundred hours. Two hundred.
帮他刺青的师傅 一定和他相处了不少时间
Tattoo artist who gave it to him must've spent a lot of time with him, then.
我去查是谁
I'll find out who it was.
-贝里克先生 -不要烦我
- Mr. Bellick. - Don't talk to me.
好，但这样会很难合作
Fine. But it's gonna make collaboration kind of hard.
合作？ 我的手下在外身处危险之中
Collaboration? I got men out here in harm's way...
你却在开记者会
...and you're giving press conferences.
媒体是工具
The press is a tool.
媒体抓到他们的速度 比猎犬还要快
It'll bring those men back quicker than bloodhounds will.
我们不需要你
We don't need you.
我们已掌握他们的行踪 抓到他们是迟早的事
We're hot on the trail, it's a matter of time till we nail them.
我不满意你只是掌握行踪
The problem I find with being on a trail...
因为这代表你永远慢猎物一步
...is that, by definition, you'll always be behind your prey.
我们走着瞧
We'll see about that.
（蒙大拿州，布拉克富特）
我手上没有武器
I'm not armed.
请见谅 我现在很难信任他人
You'll have to excuse me if I'm a little short on trust at the moment.
我向你保证，小姐 我绝对不会伤害你
I assure you, young woman, I'm the furthest thing from a threat.
我确定我吃了止痛药 全身无力
I think the Percocet pretty much ensures that.
很好，那么你应该不介意 我拍下证据给子孙欣赏
Good. Then you won't mind if I capture this moment for posterity.
你拍照也没用的
Won't do you any good.
某人因为谋杀你的罪名要被处死 你都毫不在乎吗？
You don't care that somebody's gonna be executed for your murder?
选择林克柏劳栽赃的人 不是我
I'm not the one who chose Lincoln Burrows as the fall guy.
那是谁？
Who did?
你姐姐，总统？
Your sister, the president?
你不懂，我是这整件事的囚犯
You don't understand. I'm a prisoner to all of this.
算了吧，你大可以出面说清楚
Oh, come on. You could've come forward.
在开始前 你就可以阻止整件事
You could've stopped this thing before it even got started.
不，我真的是囚犯
No, I really am a prisoner.
现在你也成了囚犯
And now you are too.
从你把门关上那一刻开始
The moment you let the door shut behind you.
外面没有保全人员
Didn't it strike you as curious...
你不觉得怪吗？
...that there wasn't any security out there?
门只能从外面打开
The doors only open from the outside.
玻璃是两寸厚的防弹玻璃
The glass is 2 inches thick, bulletproof.
你逃不出去了，小姐
There's no getting out of here, young woman.
我们得甩掉他们
We gotta dump them now.
没办法 他们知道犹他州的事了
Can't. They know about Utah.
所以更该甩掉他们
All the more reason to dump them.
他们要是被抓，调查局就会清楚知道 我们的去向，他们会说出去
If they get caught, the feds will know where we're going. They'll tell them.
我们只需让他们不被抓到 直到我们到达犹他州
We just gotta make sure they stay afloat till we're off in Utah.
我们别无他法了
Doing what we gotta do.
你真的认为那里有钱？
You really think the money's gonna be there?
查理的话可信度也许不高
Charles might've had a flexible relationship with the truth...
可是到最后 他没有必要撒这种谎
...but at the end... At the end, there'd be no reason for him to lie about it.
我打算拿到钱 我们就逃到墨西哥
I figure once we bag it, we cross over into Mexico.
接着搭老旧的公车 一路到巴拿马
Take a whole bunch of bumpy second-class bus rides till we hit Panama.
-你真的很想开潜水用品店吗？ -没错
- You really got a fix on this dive shop thing? - Yeah.
现在要我躺在吊床上 躺十年、二十年我都不在意
Right now, I wouldn't mind swinging in a hammock for the next 10, 20 years.
半个国家的人都在追捕我们 我们到不了巴拿马或犹他州
We got half the country after us. We ain't making it to Panama or Utah.
要有人帮助才可以
Not without help.
哩诺卡帮不了我们
Veronica can't help us.
你这么有信心？
How can you say that?
-我们没有钱、衣服 -我都准备好了
- We don't have money, clothes... - We got all that.
我以为计划是亚布兹的飞机
I thought the plan was Abruzzi's jet.
飞机只是A计划
Abruzzi's jet was plan A.
-那么我们 -一应俱全
- Then we got... - Everything we need.
在哪里？
Where?
我藏起来了
Storage.
（时机成熟树林）
刺青是史柯菲设计的？ 不是你？
Scofield designed the tattoo, not you?
（FBI办公室 芝加哥，伊利诺州）
He brought the entire thing in. Every element.
设计图都是他带来的 所有细节
你看，这个刺青很仔细 这可是西斯汀礼拜堂
I mean, look at it. It's the frigging sistine Chapel.
我知道他是工程师，可是
I know the guy was an engineer, but, man...
他真的很有艺术天分
...his skill as an artist was unbelievable.
还有什么？ 你觉得他这个人如何？
What else? What can you tell me about him as a person?
他很冷静
He was cool, you know.
但是他很要求细节 一切都要完美
But talk about a detail Nazi. Everything had to be perfect.
刺青要和设计图一模一样 我一直觉得整件事
Exactly as he drew it. I always sort of had the feeling...
是个只有他自己了解的笑话
...that the whole thing was some sort of inside joke that only he was in on.
（英格利、费兹、波西）
我们有你的电话对吧？
We have your number, right?
对
Yeah.
我可能会和你联络，谢谢
I may be calling you. Thank you.
富利
Foley.
我们到监狱的那条 很长的路叫什么？
What was the name of that road to get to the prison?
我想是英格利街
I think it was English street.
（英格利街）
还有监狱前方 两条交叉的路叫什么？
In front of the prison, the two streets that intersect with it?
-费兹街和波西大道，怎么了？ -谢谢
- Fitz and Percy. Why? - Thank you.
-准备出发 -我们要去哪？
- Saddle up. - Where we going?
我们不再是犯人 恢复老百姓身分的地方
Somewhere we can stop being cons and start being civilians.
说话不要拐弯抹角 有话直说好吗？
Yo, why don't you cut out all the riddles, snowflake, and just give it to us straight?
怎么了？
What?
-你们好 -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
你好，小朋友
Well, hey, little one.
你们在做什么？
What are you doing?
我们
Well...
在钓鱼
We're just fishing.
不用钓杆？
With no poles?
我们喜欢用手抓鱼
Well, we like to fish with our hands.
对，用手抓鱼
Yeah, that's it. Hand-fishing.
我想重点是
I think the question is...
你在这里做什么？
...what are you doing out here?
-打猎 -葛蕾西？
- Hunting. - Gracie?
快离开退后
Get away, Gracie. Get away. Get back.
你们是福克斯河监狱的逃犯
You're those guys from Fox River.
不准你们任何人移动分毫
Don't any of you move a freaking muscle.
离她远一点
Get away from her. Get away from her!
好，你别激动
Okay, okay. Just relax.
冷静一下
Relax.
-先生 -留在原地
- Sir... - You stay where you are.
-不要，约翰 -把枪放下
- No, no! John! - Put the gun down! Put the gun down.
-放开她 -马上
- Let her go! - Right now!
-放开她 -约翰，把女孩放开
- Let her go! - John, let go of the girl.
-闭嘴 -放开她
- Shut up! - Let her go.
把枪放下
Put it down. Drop the gun.
把枪放下，马上给我放下
You drop the gun. Drop it now.
给我把枪放下
You put the gun down.
一
One...
我要开枪了
I'm gonna pull the trigger.
二
Two!
好孩子，好孩子
Good boy. Good boy.
把枪捡起来
Get the gun.
捡起来！
Pick it up!
-不准你伤害她 -嘿！
- Don't you hurt her. Don't you lay a... - Hey!
不会有事的
Gonna be all right.
对不对？
Right?
回去爸爸身边
Run to Daddy.
我不会说出去的
I ain't gonna say anything to anybody, man.
我们不会伤害你，请你冷静 你的车在哪里？
You're not gonna get hurt, so just calm down. Where's your car?
-道路旁 -我需要你的钥匙
- Up on the road. - I need your keys.
你现在疑似是本案共犯
You're being considered an accessory to this.
这你应该知道吧？
You know that, don't you?
我现在知道的不多
I know very little right now.
你把医务室的门打开 让史柯菲逃跑
You opened the door to the infirmary that allowed scofield to escape.
-对不对？ -不对
- Didn't you? - No.
-你和史柯菲有性关系吗？ -没有
- You have a sexual relationship with him? - No.
可是你对他有感情
But you had feelings for him.
还有其他七个人一起逃走了
Seven other men got out, you know.
还有谁？
Who?
（马文古达兽医院）
先生，抱歉，今天周六不营业
I'm sorry, sir, it's saturday. We're not open.
所以我才会来
Well, that's sort of the point.
什么意思？先生
Sorry, sir?
是这样的，我需要治疗 要私底下治疗
See, I'm gonna need some work done and I'm gonna need it done privately.
抱歉，你说“你”需要治疗？
I'm sorry, you said you needed the work done?
这里是诊所不是吗？
This is a medical clinic, isn't it?
先生，当然是 可是这里是兽医院
Well, of course it is, sir, but for animals.
天啊，你出了什么事？
God, man, what happened to you?
你需要就医
You need medical attention.
-等等 -我去通知救护车
- No. - I'm gonna get an ambulance.
不准你通知任何人，医生
Nobody's gonna be doing any calling here, doctor.
好
Fine.
很好
That's right.
你要做什么？
What do you want?
知道吗？我受够了
You know what? That's it.
我要那个疯子立刻下车 她只是个小女孩
I want Eyetie out of the car right now, man. That was a little girl.
你没有良心吗？
Don't you have a heart?
我有女儿，一个小女儿
God, I have a daughter. I have a little girl.
我也有个女儿
I got one too.
但我刚刚如果不这么做
But if I hadn't done what I had to do...
我们现在就无法去看女儿了 不是吗？
...we wouldn't be on our way to see them right now.
前面右转
Turn right up there.
等等，要去哪里？
Whoa, hold on. Where we going?
奥斯威哥
Oswego.
那是西方，我们要往东走才对 我的家人在芝加哥
That's west, man. We need to go east. My family's back in Chicago.
你认为警察不知道吗？
And you think the cops don't know about it?
你不认为他们会坐在你家
You think they're not just sitting there...
等着你直接跑回去吗？
...waiting for you to come running back home?
你到底在想什么？
What's the matter with you?
-那纽约呢？ -纽约怎么了？
- What about New York? - What about it?
我的女友怀孕了，老哥
My girl's pregnant, bro.
想清楚，现在你爱的人 正是你的弱点
Understand, your love is your weakness right now.
-警察都知道 -不代表不能去见她们
- And they know about it. - Doesn't mean it has to stop you.
只要行事谨慎
You just gotta be smart about it.
还有要到达奥斯威哥
And get to oswego.
奥斯威哥不顺路，小白脸
Oswego is not on the way, snowflake.
重点不在奥斯威哥的位置
It's not where oswego is.
而是奥斯威哥有什么东西
It's what's in oswego.
队长，史柯菲的信用卡纪录
Captain, scofield's credit-card transaction history.
他在入狱前 在威尔郡花了很多钱
Spent money in Will County before he was incarcerated.
-没错 -他是芝加哥人
- Exactly. - He's from Chicago.
为何从芝加哥跑来这里
Why does a guy from Chicago come here...
在一个多月内 就花了八千美金？
...and spend 8 grand in all these places in a month?
洗车、语音信箱、仓库、租车
Car wash, voice mail, storage, car rental.
-已经在查了 -很好
- We got guys looking into it. - Good.
-队长，要告诉FBI吗？ -你觉得呢？
- What about the feds? Should we tell? - What do you think?
贝里克队长，有消息了
Captain Bellick, we got something.
松树林中 有位猎人遇见五个犯人
Hunter up by Tamarack just ran into five of the cons.
这里就是史柯菲住的地方
So this is where scofield lived.
对，直到两个月前 他入狱服刑
Yeah, up until about two months ago when he was incarcerated.
母亲过世，父亲是游手好闲的人
Mother's dead, father's a deadbeat.
全世界只剩下哥哥一个亲人
Got nothing in the whole world but your brother.
于是你就开始计划
So you plan.
花好几个月策划
And you scheme for months...
直到找到最好的办法
...until you get it right.
计划出每一个环节
Every single element.
接着你摧毁所有的证据
And then you destroy all the evidence.
派潜水夫到河里搜索
I want divers down in the river.
手机不会有讯号的
You won't get cell coverage.
这里是荒郊野外
We're in the middle of nowhere.
西蒙大拿州 不会有数位基地台的
Those digital carriers don't have cell towers way out here in Western Montana.
-你闭嘴好吗？戴伦斯 -我只想让你省去麻烦
- How about shutting up, Terrence? - Just trying to save you some effort.
这些人像蜘蛛网 你越挣扎情况越糟糕
They're like a web, these people. Harder you struggle, worse it gets.
听起来像是个懦夫 想自圆其说
Sounds to me like a coward trying to justify himself.
只要我不碍事、闭上嘴 我就能保命
If I stay out of the way and stay quiet, I stay alive.
他们是这样告诉我的
That's what they said. That's what they told me.
你想继续过这种生活？ 活在密闭空间里
And you want to live like this? In a hermetically sealed box...
-外面的世界都不在乎？ -为了自保，人什么都做得出来
...while everything out there goes to hell? - Self-preservation is a strong motivator.
为了真相也是
So's the truth.
不要
Don't.
小姐
Young woman.
不要打
Do not.
不要
Don't.
你还好吗？朋友
How you doing, buddy?
我还好吗？我快吓死了
I'm pretty freaked out, that's how I'm doing.
他们抢走你的车对吧？
They took your car, didn't they?
1978年的大却若奇车？
1978 Grand Cherokee?
-对 -他们往哪里去？
- Yeah. - Which way did they go?
往那边，往北走，到奥斯威哥
Up that way. North, toward oswego.
奥斯威哥，失陪
Oswego. Pardon me.
史柯菲的资料给我
Scofield's paperwork, get it to me.
信用卡资料
That credit card stuff.
在这里，队长
Right here, captain.
（艾伦自助仓储）
当然了
Of course.
他需要消失的东西 还能放哪呢？
Where else you gonna put all the crap you need to disappear?
前往奥斯威哥，各位
We're going to oswego, boys.
有访客找你
You have a visitor.
谢谢
Thank you.
Thanks.
你的表情很失望
You look disappointed.
没有，我以为访客是我的父亲
No, I thought you were gonna be my father.
他有和你联络吗？
You heard from him?
他的办公室有
His office.
我带换洗衣服来给你
Well, brought you a change of clothes.
-我想会需要的 -谢谢
- Figured, you know. - Thanks.
还有你的皮包
And your purse.
你留在医务室没带走
You left it in the infirmary.
我想我的麻烦大了
I'm in a lot of trouble, I think.
我
I...
我要向你道歉
I need to apologize to you.
如果我不说 他们就威胁要开除我
They threatened my job if I didn't talk, and...
不
No, no. No.
在人生的过程中 你会领悟到
One thing you learn when you're walking the steps...
自己犯的错 不要去牵连或责怪他人
...is that you never outsource the blame that belongs in your own back yard.
好吧
Well...
你不是第一个爱上犯人的职员
...you're not the first correctional worker that fell for a con.
相信我
Trust me.
他根本不在乎我
He never cared.
我对他毫无意义
Not one bit.
你在想什么？
What are you thinking about?
我犯的错
Mistakes.
你非做不可
You had to do it.
但我的方式错了
Not like I did.
我毁了她的人生
I ruined her life.
-你现在也爱莫能助 -不对
- There's nothing you can do about it now. - That's not true.
你喜欢她，对吧？
You fell for her, huh?
奥斯威哥在哪里？
Where's oswego?
还有约半里的路程
Half a mile, maybe.
很好
Good.
你打算开枪杀我吗？戴伦斯
What are you gonna do, Terrence, shoot me?
把我打得血肉横飞？ 然后呢？
Blow my guts all over the house? Then what?
你走不了，记得吗？
You can't leave, remember?
你杀了我，尸体也走不了
You kill me, you're stuck with me.
我在这里很安全
I'm safe here.
你是个囚犯
You're a prisoner here.
但是我还活着
But I'm still breathing.
只要我踏出去
If I go outside...
一步我就死了
...one step, I won't be.
你认为我是没良心的魔鬼？
You look at me like I'm the devil.
我丢下我的家人
I gave up my family.
还有我的牙齿，我每天都在吃止痛药
My teeth. I eat Percocet all day...
以抑制我悲惨生命的痛楚
...just to dull the pain of my miserable existence.
-你根本不了解我受的苦 -你受的苦？
- You have no idea what I've been through. - What you've been through?
重点不在你身上，戴伦斯
This isn't about you, Terrence.
不要
Don't.
布拉克富特郡警局
Blackfoot Sheriff's Department,
喂？布拉克富特郡警局
Hello? Blackfoot Sheriff's Department,
你好 我叫哩诺卡唐纳凡
Hello, my name's Veronica Donovan.
请你尽快派警车 到光明路底的房子
I need you to send a unit to the house at the end of Light Road as soon as possible.
小姐，抱歉，你是要报案吗？
I'm sorry, ma'am, are you calling to report a crime?
对
Yeah.
犯罪人是美国总统
By the president of the United states.
派警车过来
Send the car.
先生抱歉，我没办法帮你
I'm sorry, sir, I don't think I can do this.
手掌有神经
There are nerves. Look...
-你需要专科医生 -我没有
- You need a specialist. - I don't...
你需要懂得治疗法的医生
You need somebody who knows what they're doing.
我没有选择余地，医生
I don't have the luxury of choice here.
我的手放在箱子里好几小时 快废掉了
My hand has been in that box for hours now. It is dying.
先生，我没有能力帮你
Sir, I am not capable of doing this.
我只有一只手，但在你到门口前 我会把这插进你脖子
I only have one hand, but I can stick this in your neck before you get to that door.
如果这么说无法激励你的话 我知道你结婚了，古达医生
Now, if that's not incentive enough for you, I see that you have a Mrs. Gudat out there.
在这一带有这种特殊姓氏
With a name like that in a county like this...
古达太太应该很好找，不是吗？
...old Mrs. Gudat would not be too hard to find, now, would she?
好吧
Fine.
但我无法给你保证
I can promise you nothing.
这是我的人生写照
Story of my life.
我得将你麻醉
I'll have to put you under.
我看起来很笨吗？
Do I really look that stupid?
先生，没有麻醉 我无法做这种手术
Sir, I cannot do a procedure like this without an anesthetic.
我得切掉坏死的组织
I have to cut away dead flesh.
一般人没有麻醉 是无法忍受这种手术的
Nobody can undergo a procedure like this without an anesthetic.
我不是一般人
I ain't nobody.
史柯菲拆掉逃走的马桶 是史威哲公司制造的
Schweitzer was the company that made the toilet scofield took off to get out of his cell.
-艾伦螺钉是马桶的配件 -都在上面，不是吗？
- The Allen bolt was the fitting. - It's all here, isn't it?
-对 -太厉害了
- Yeah. - It's amazing.
时机成熟树林 这附近有这个地名吗？
Ripe Chance Woods. Is there a place in the vicinity with that name?
我派了人去查
Got someone looking into it.
矫正局正前往 奥斯威哥的一座仓库
DoC's moving on a storage facility in oswego.
（艾伦仓储）
队长，经理说史柯菲租了 164号仓库，还在使用中
Captain, manager says that scofield's got a lease on Unit 164. still active.
A街、第三街和峡谷都有派人
We have guys on 8th street, 3rd street and in the alley.
-如果他们在那里，就逃不掉了 -全力逮捕他们
- Lf they're in there, we got them boxed. - We push right up the gut, then.
他们只要有人作势威胁 就开枪轰了他们
Any one of them makes a threatening move, put a hole in them.
没问题
You got it.
警官
Officer.
这是我的逮捕行动，聪明的家伙 你休想插手
This is my collar, smart guy. Back the hell off.
把门关上
Close the door.
（时机成熟树林）
还是查不到这个地方？
Still nothing on this place?
没有，都查不到资料
Nope. They're coming back with nothing.
国内没有这个地名
No place by that name anywhere in this country...
其他国家也没有这个地名
...or any other country for that matter.
我们走
Let's go.
我们被那浑蛋耍了
Son of a bitch set us up.
什么都不准说
Not one word.
警官
Officer.
（瑞佛斯）
（伍兹）
没事
Nothing.
这小子真聪明
Oh, that kid's clever.
那不是地名，是人名
It's not a place, it's a name.
-你有带掌上型电脑吗？ -有
- Your PDA, you got it? - Yeah.
查出本郡的人口资料
Bring up the census of this county.
资料越久越好
Far back as it goes.
-我们一定会被发现 -继续挖
- Well, somebody's gonna see us. - Keep digging.
我们一定会下地狱，各位 我说真的，我们会下地狱
We're gonna go to hell, guys. Swear to God, we're gonna go to hell.
帮我接过去
Help me out.
你真的很变态，你知道吗？
You are one sick cat, you know that?
你在找什么？
What are you looking for?
我们要去墓园
We gotta go to the cemetery.
现在
Now.
原本这应该是 我和林克一周要用的衣服
Originally, this was supposed to be a week's worth of clothes for me and Linc.
不过你们和我们一样需要帮助
But I figured you all need just as much help as we do, so...
你这么做是出自良心吗？
You're doing this out of the goodness of your heart?
约翰，没错，良心 你没忘记良心是什么吧？
Right, John, the heart. You remember what that is, don't you?
小白脸，这衣服真棒
Damn, snowflake, this is tight, man.
如我所说，我们不能再当犯人了
It's like I said, we gotta stop being cons...
要开始当一般老百姓
...start being civilians.
不错，但你不觉得裤子太短了？
Nice. The trousers are a little bit too short, don't you think?
把你的腿砍掉，你最在行
Chop your feet off. You're good at that.
这件夹克不太好看，你懂吗？
This jacket isn't exactly the best thing.
你想要选择？ 就去大卖场吧
- You know what I'm saying? - You want variety, hit Target.
林克
Linc.
这是什么？
What have we got?
钱、护照
Money, passports...
预付电话卡
...prepaid phone cards.
-阿奇莱恩？ -有看过我的吗？
- Archie Ryan? - You see mine?
费尼亚斯麦克林塔
Phineas McClintock.
这是什么？
Whoa, and these?
有辆车在等着我们 在几百码外
Keys to a car that's waiting for us a couple of hundred yards from here.
两人座还是五人座？
That a two-of-us or five-of-us?
两人座的车
That's a two-of-us.
-他们知道吗？ -还不知道
- They know? - Not yet.
各位，有人来了
Guys, guys. We got company.
（RIP 钱斯树林，愿他安息）
我们快走吧
We gotta roll.
他怎么会知道？
How did he know?
我们是老百姓，不要忘了
We're civilians. Remember that.
我们是老百姓
We're civilians.
-抱歉，你知道现在几点了？ -不知道，抱歉
- I'm sorry. Do you know what time it is? - No, I'm sorry.
我不能出去 只要我一露面，他们就会杀了我
I can't go outside. They'll kill me as soon as I show my face.
你错了
You're wrong about that.
只要你一出面 整件事就可以结束了
As soon as you show your face, this whole thing is gonna be over.
你可以恢复你的人生，戴伦斯
You can have your life back, Terrence.
-你保证？ -我保证
- Promise? - I promise.
喂？
Hello?
小哩，是我
V, it's me.
-林克？ -我们逃出来了
- Linc? - We're out,
感谢老天你没事，我看到新闻了 你们不要逃了
oh, thank God you're okay. I saw the news. You gotta stop.
-我要你去自首 -为什么？
- I need you to turn yourself in, - What?
我找到史泰门，跟他在一起 林克，他还活着
I found steadman. I'm with him now, Linc. He's alive.
我可以证明你无罪
You're gonna be exonerated.
-请进 -史泰门？
- Come in. - Steadman?
你说什么？你找到史泰门？
What are you talking, you found steadman?
-戴伦斯，我们走吧 -午安
- Terrence, come on, let's go. - Afternoon.
-哩诺卡 -警察来了
- Veronica, - The police are here.
听着，你留在原地
Look, I need you to stay where you are.
-小姐 -我不想失去你
- Ma'am, - I don't wanna lose you.
-小姐，把电话挂掉 -什么？
- Ma'am, put the phone down. - What?
史泰门先生，请你后退
Mr. Steadman, take a few steps back.
哩哩诺卡？
Ver... Veronica?
哩诺卡？
Veronica?
天啊
Oh, my God.
哩
Veronica!
我以为你知道，我们会过滤 所有打去地方警局的电话
I thought you knew that all calls to the local station are routed through us.
这是联邦土地，记得吗？
This is federal land, remember?
至于你的小玩具，这是违禁品
And as for your little toy here. It's contraband.
-麻烦告诉我们你是怎么带进来的？ -我进来时就带在身上
- You gonna tell us how you got it in there? - I brought it when I got here.
-目的何在？ -保护我自己
- Whatever for? - To protect myself.
那是我们的职责，记得吗？
That's what we're here for, remember?
（有个计划可导正一切）
区区一天线索就消失了
In less than a day, the trail has gone cold,,,
警方正追捕 所谓的福克斯河八逃犯
,,, in pursuit of what are being called the Fox River Eight...
好，继续追踪，懂吗？
That's fine. Stay on top of it, all right?
矫正局还在搜奥斯威哥 但这些人根本就像消失了
DoC's still doing a sweep of oswego but they have basically vanished.
-我可不这么想，埃福斯先生 -我不知道你的自信是哪来的？
- I wouldn't be sure about that, Ives. - Don't know how you can be so confident.
他们又没有留下逃亡地图
It's not like they left a map where they're going.
事实上，他们就是留了
Actually, that's exactly what they did.
史柯菲把整个计划刺在身上
Scofield had the entire thing on his body.
记载着越狱的办法 之后消失的方法
How to get out of that prison, how to disappear afterward,
全都在刺青上
It's all there,
我向你保证 假以时日就会查出
I promise you that it's only a matter of time before we know everything...
史柯菲脑中的一切
...that is in scofield's head.
他的逃亡地点 逃去该地的方式
Where he plans to run to, how he plans to get there,
等到他真的到达该地时
So when the time comes that he does get there,,,
我们就会在那里等着他
...we'll be waiting for him.